this i have enough in my journal
i'm gonna
publish this i'm out
[Music]
hello my name is matt corley
tonight we're going to talk about
watergate
let's begin washington dc
1907 1972 five
watergate burglars are arrested in the
democratic national committee
headquarters
what are they doing there why are they
breaking in
the young upstart reporter robert
woodward
goes to the hearing one of them
when the judge is asking these five
burglars
who do you work for the c.i.a
excuse me could you say a little bit
louder the c.i.a
robert woodward is on to something
oh look at this sweet little fat guy
where do you gotta be right now
okay let's go back in time the year is
1970.
a young robert woodward
a lieutenant in the navy he's sitting
next to this
older distinguished man saying
i'm soon to be out of the navy what am i
going to do with my life
am i gonna become a lawyer like my
father wants
and this older man present himself as a
mentor saying
so listen to me you're working for truth
stay with it and young robert woodward
takes away from this thing
i can depend on this man i can call on
this man
at some point to give me information
that man is mark felt deputy director
of the fbi let's flash forward a little
bit
robert woodward and his partner carl
bernstein decide to call in his old
buddy
mark felt for information about
watergate
felt says i can't talk to you on the
phone about this i'm mark felt
and i did spy times in world war ii
and i know how this works you get the
new york times
every day at your door at page 20
i will draw a little clock that says
what hour i want to meet you and here's
the thing
anytime you want to meet me mark felt
says i need
something that i could visually
acknowledge
woodward says i do have this potted
plant that i keep out on my balcony i
could move that
and mark felt is like here's the thing i
want to meet you at this underground
parking garage
in virginia but anytime you want to meet
leave out the back
stairs walk a couple of blocks get in
the cab
take that cab get out of the cab walk a
couple blocks get in
another cab get in that cab get out of
that cab
walk couple blocks to the virginia
parking garage that i
previously talked about woodward meets
felt and he says
sorry pal
i'm ready to tell the story
woodward meets with mark felt
and he says could you tell me a little
bit about
why these guys might be connected
and he says put the pieces together you
dumbass
it's all in front of you do the work
just be careful watergate is the tip of
the iceberg
and when robert woodward took his secret
source to the washington post he said
my source is deep background that means
he cannot be identified
their editor at the washington post said
yeah you keep calling him deep
background but i'm going to call him
deep
throat based on the pornography film
that was very popular which dealt with
natural ladies
you know and so woodward
and bernstein figure out that this money
connected to these burglars go all the
way to the
watergate administration to the nixon
administration
richard nixon let's talk about richard
nixon do you want to talk about richard
nixon
yes please i thought you might mark
phelps says
to nixon i'm the deputy director of the
fbi
i'm gonna look into his rascal deep
throat and further
i'm gonna set myself up as head of the
investigation
so nixon's top eight haldeman says
i think mark felt his deep throat and
nixon says
now why would he do that and when the
watergate hearings
gets to a boiling point nixon is like i
never knew of this watergate break-in to
discover
information about the democrats and
after that he says
i am not a crook nixon knows he's
and he says there's nothing i can do
about it nobody's gonna trust me at this
point
i gotta step down hand me some cookies
all i know is i'm eating cookies and
none of you are
do you guys want some cookies i know
we'd like watching
you have no ambition the interesting
thing about this day we're taking on it
is
all the stories we know of watergate is
whose deep throat
now we can tell the story knowing who
is
and in the end you can toss aside
richard nixon
for all his cynicism you can toss aside
deep throat for all his cynicism
but you can't toss aside robert
woodward and to a lesser extent carl
bernstein for the
truth that they exposed for america
well we told the story of watergate
there's no way it could possibly
misconstrued as
not the greatest journalistic
endeavor ever told robert woodward would
be proud
hello i'm katie nolan and today we're
gonna talk
about gloria steinem
our story begins in the year 1963.
gloria steinem was a graduate of smith
college
very smart she's 28 years old and she's
a journalist
and show magazine was like hey gloria we
have a story for you
we want you to go undercover at one of
hugh hefner's playboy clubs
and playboy clubs were advertising
themselves at the time as like
being in a real live version of playboy
so you would have like beautiful women
everywhere and drinks and food and
dude stuff yeah boobies and vaginas
and gloria was like i don't think this
is what i want i want people to take me
seriously
and our editor was like i think this
could be your chance to call hugh hefner
out on his
goddamn and she was like you're
right
i'm in let's do it
um uh what was i talking about
so she says yes to the thing to the
assignment
and so she goes to the audition which is
at a playboy club so
she's this alias she's created for
herself which is marie
catherine oaks and the woman that she
goes up to says
take off your coat let me see your body
gloria was like um
okay and like took her coat off the
woman was like
you look a little old for 24
but your body's great come back on
saturday
for a fitting and so gloria comes back a
couple days later
she sees this woman named cherylie she's
like i'm the bunny mother
so she goes and she gets size she puts
on this leotard and she's like this fits
and they're like no it doesn't
and they keep going in and in and
gloria's like
i think that's right enough i can hardly
breathe
i said an ice cube just assaulted me you
got isis
[Laughter]
so the bunny mother cherylee is
explaining to the bunnies
there's all these things that they can
take your money away for like if your
ears are on crooked
that's a demerit if your bunny tail is
dirty that's demerits
if you're not smiling enough that's a
bunch of demerits
they also give her this bunny manual
which is a list of all the rules that
you have to follow
in the bunny manual it says you're not
allowed to date
any customers but then they were told
unless they hold
the special key these special key
members
were allowed to do whatever they want ew
that's up anyway
so they're like great you're all set
you're gonna start work soon we just
need you to complete your physical
and gloria's like what do you mean i'm
gonna be a waitress
oh well we just need you to complete a
physical with this doctor and then
you'll be fine to start
desk grows yeah that's just gross
so she goes to the doctor she sits on
the table and she sees there's
stirrups and the doctor walks in
and the first thing he says to her is so
you want to be a bunny
which is alarming as a doctor
he exams her which to a woman means
you know did you say pap patch
have you ever had one it's not a bagel
derek it's a it's
i'm from the yard i'm not getting rid of
the passage
so she finishes the exam and
she goes the next day to train for this
job that's a fancy word for
you're gonna work and not get paid any
money she's training as a table bunny
and they teach her that she just has to
follow the other
bunny servers around and so she's going
around asking people like
hello i'm bunny marie what can i get for
you
and they would say things like yeah girl
let me see your titties
open it up which is
how many times are you allowed to say
on comedy center i've said it a
whole bunch whatever you want
okay it's some she's working
all these shifts and she's like in her
journal she's writing all these
injustices
they're like working these long hours
they're not making any money
on top of that it's basically a
prostitution ring and
after working in the playboy clubs for
four weeks
gloria was like this i have enough
in my journal
i'm gonna publish this i'm out
it's just all this stupid sexist dumb
ass
she just wanted to get the and so she
quit
and so gloria writes an expose on these
playboy clubs
she's like these women were like not
making as much money as they were told
they were gonna make
it's insane hours they're being grabbed
all the time
they're treated like prostitutes they're
basically being used as a
tool for the male sexual revolution
but the women themselves don't get to
own their sexuality
and that's shitty um
so they published they publishes
they publ they publish they
publish the story in the magazine
so the world reads this article and to
his
very tiny credit hugh hefner says wow
yeah maybe they won't have to go to
these physical exams anymore
and you know what i'm gonna stop making
them have to give so much of their money
to us
if they make a mistake which is like a
really cool thing
that hugh hefner did um but also
not as cool as just like always treating
them that way
this article made gloria steinem a
household name
and she went on to be this huge feminist
icon it's tough but i swear to god if it
weren't for gloria steinem i wouldn't be
able to be on tv
it's very hard to be a woman that's like
i love sports
and you have stuck to your gums ever
since you started and that
is what you cried i'm sorry
can i get somebody else to do do this
hello i'm going to tell you about nellie
bly a very good journalist from the
1880s
who did an expose in the world
of mental illness
nilly bly was a very strong-minded woman
she gets a load of
a column from a local pittsburgh paper
and it's super sexist the article was
like
chicks gotta in the kitchen
girls gotta why even bother being
educated when you just gotta get married
and have
babies and she was like this guy
girls are better than being in the
kitchen being wives and sewing
i'm super smart and i'm going to show
you i'm super smart
just to prove that like women are
awesome
so nelly so nelly bly
went to new york city and she knocked on
every
newspaper door in the city and who
answered the door
joseph pulitzer himself and he's like
listen i don't take you seriously
but i have an assignment i want you to
pretend to be crazy and get committed to
the insane asylum of new york city
black calls the island nellie bly
said okay i'll do it and he was like
what and she was like i will go into the
insane asylum and give you a really good
report
right right
all right so lily blair she never saw a
crazy person before
so she went in front of a mirror and
made
funny faces like
this face his
she face no idea what crazy people to
say is it
she was like okay this is how i'm gonna
be crazy
she goes to this bro this boarding house
listen everybody
every listen every every lady at this
boarding house with me
i am crazy okay
what what
oh you're crazy nellie
you're crazy you're crazy
yes you're crazy the head mistress is
like the center of the insane asylum
and nelly obliges like yes this is
working
this is super working for me i'm super
happy
and she finds herself on blackwell's
[Music]
island
um
i'm drunk
so she was examined by a doctor like how
tall is she
and the nurse would be like come and
look at how tall
this nellie is and doctor would say
like what are you doing after we
measured nellie blood
after the nurse and doctor flirted for
like a half hour
uh the doctor's like oh my god
this nelly bligh she is a crazy crazy
person that needs to be here forever
and nelly blind was like yes
i'm so happy i'm such a good journalist
she started to see how the conditions
were the nurses would just beat the
out of people
knock them in their ears
hitting them like crazy like you women
are all crazy and you suck and nellie
blair was like oh
that ain't cool i'm gonna write that
down these ladies are gonna get a word
from me
she sees perfectly sane women who just
don't speak english the
doctors are like we don't speak german
you're crazy
you go to the asylum for life and there
was a woman
she was like i just got a little
overwhelmed i'm not
crazy and they were like this woman
isn't
so insane there's nothing we can do but
keep her locked up with this in asylum
forever
because the insane asylum was horrible
and then
there's the baths the nurses would just
scrub the out of him and nellie bly
would be like this kind of hurts a
little bit
she was like you be quiet or i will i
will
i will make you wish you never said
anything to me i'll scrub you so hard
wow i got at least two bathing suits
should we put them on and get in the tub
really you don't have the balls to get
in the tub with me with the bathing suit
to you
look to the ceiling derrick look oh
you're so much more pleasant than water
over your heads
than my son he makes such a fuss this is
such a delight
nellie bly had to take baths with like
the dirt 45 other girls on her and it
was
freezing cold
she had this horrible
10 days in an insane asylum
and then joseph paul is just like hey
guess what dummies
like this crazy way of girl was my sweet
reporter
and she um
and she
she wasn't insane when they were like oh
no
we're exposed and she
wrote an article that exposed everybody
all of a sudden money was flowing like
crazy to mental health institutions
she changed the world of mental health
nellie blair was one of the first great
american feminists
that said listen stupid 1880s guys with
giant mustaches connected to their
stupid sideburns
women were really cool
that's basically how it went except less
[Music]
kissing
you